solarwinds.com 2016-05-06

# Solarwinds - Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Statement describes the types of information SolarWinds Worldwide, LLC and its subsidiaries (“SolarWinds”) collect from and about you when you visit our website (“Website”) and identifies how SolarWinds may use and share such information as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.

* Data Collection 

_Information You Provide to Us_. SolarWinds collects information from you when you choose to provide it to us. Any information that is provided by you to us via the Website or otherwise will be treated in accordance applicable data protection law. Such information may be provided to us when you download and install a product for evaluation or trial, download and install a free tool, request a quote from us, purchase or register a product, sign up for newsletters, white papers, our email list, or other assets offered by SolarWinds, create a user account on our Website, customer portal or community forum, submit a customer service or technical support ticket, or otherwise contact us. The personal information we collect may include your name, address, email address, telephone number, screen or user name, information about the products that you own and use, or—if you’re a SolarWinds customer—your payment information. You may be required to provide certain information to create your account or complete your purchase for certain jurisdictions. If you use a third party login to create your account or otherwise link to us, we may receive certain information about you from the third party (such as social network) based on your registration and privacy settings on that third party service.

_Information We Automatically Collect_. SolarWinds may use cookies, web beacons, or other technologies to automatically collect certain information when you visit our Website, interact with our emails, within the SolarWinds products, or in online advertisements. A cookie, also known as an HTTP cookie, web cookie, or browser cookie, is usually a small piece of data sent from the Website and stored in a user's web browser while a user is browsing the Website. Cookies were designed to be a reliable mechanism for websites to remember the state of the website or activity the user had taken in the past. This can include automatically collecting information such as your IP address, browser type, operating system, software version, referrer ID and the domain from which you accessed the Website. When the user browses the Website in the future, the data stored in the cookie can be retrieved by the Website to notify the Website of the user's previous activity. SolarWinds also may collect information about your use of the Website, such as the time you spend using the Website, the number of times you return, whether you click-through, open, or forward links, emails, and ads, and other Website usage data.

Other kinds of cookies include authentication cookies, which are the most common method used by web servers to recognise whether the user is logged in or not and the account they are logged in under. Without such a mechanism, the Website would not know whether it is authorized to send a page containing sensitive information or whether it should require a user to authenticate himself/herself by logging-in.

SolarWinds uses cookies that are hosted internally and that are provided by service providers to analyze users’ usage of the Website. This facilitates on-going improvements to the Website and improves the customer experience with SolarWinds and its products. We also use cookies that are hosted internally to allow users to authenticate themselves on successive visits to the Website. This allows users to gain access to authorised content.

Service | Function | Cookie Details | Cookie Type  
---|---|---|---  
Authentication Cookies | These cookies allow users to authenticate themselves on successive visits to the Website and gain access to authorised content. | See details below. | First Party1  
Analytical Cookies | These cookies allow us to generate anonymous customer usage statistics, and they differentiate requests from different browsers and to store helpful information. |  All these cookies, provided by SolarWinds, are prefixed with “s_”. 

SolarWinds will provide the cookie detail below for all cookies that are provided by a third party.

|  First Party 

Third Party   
  
Authentication Cookies |  |  |   
---|---|---|---  
HttpBrowserCookieCheck | Confirms that all cookies are enabled on a browser. | HttpBrowserCookieCheck |  First Party; 

Persistent2  
  
ASP.NET | This cookie is needed to enable the user to visit the site, use its features, and to access secure portions of the site. | ASP.NET_SessionId |  First Party; 

Session3  
  
Analytical Cookies |  |  |   
---|---|---|---  
SilverPop | These cookies enable us to deliver content specific to a visitor’s interest and improves convenience and efficiency. | All cookies are prefixed with “com.silverpop” |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Mbox | These cookies measure the performance of the page content for A/B split testing. | All these cookies are prefixed with “CT-“ or “mbox.“ |  First Party; 

Persistent   
  
Site Catalyst (also called “Omniture”) |  These cookie gathers information about how long a user takes to proceed to the “Download” button and also how much time they spend on a download page. 

It also helps to anonymously define new visitors, help analyze click-stream data, and track historical activity on the web site such as campaign response or sales cycle analysis. 

| This cookie is prefixed with “s_”. |  First Party; 

Persistent   
  
Referral Cookie | This cookie provides information about whether the visitor is a direct visitor (previous visitor), organic (new visitor coming directly to the site), or referred (if they are coming from another site, a banner ad, etc.) to the SolarWinds site. | This is identified as “Referral Cookie.” |  First Party; 

Session   
  
AddThis | This cookie allows us to track whether a unique visitor shares the content in social media or other platforms. | These cookies are labelled as: _atuvc, dt, uid. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Ektron | These cookies allow the website to remember selections that a visitor makes, such as a language preferences, geographical region, and user name. | These cookies are labelled as: Ecm and EktGUID. |  First Party; 

Session   
  
Adobe TagManager | This cookie is used for personalizing user experiences by tracking a visitor’s behavior on applicable webpages. | This cookie is prefixed with “CT-”. |  Third Party; 

Session   
  
Flashtalking | This cookie is an online ad server used for measuring display and affiliate activity and may be used for retargeting and conversion.  | This cookie is labelled as ad1. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Google Analytics | These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors utilize the site. It tracks visitor behaviour and measures site performance. | These cookies are identified as: __utma - Google Analytics tracking cookie, expires immediately; __utmb - Google Analytics tracking cookie, expires in 30 minutes; __utmc - Google Analytics tracking cookie, session cookie, expires at end of session; and __utmz - Google Analytics tracking cookie, expires in 6 months, 12 hours and 30 minutes. |  First Party; 

Persistent   
  
Qualaroo (formerly KissInsights) | These cookies are used on pages that identify unique visitors of pop-up surveys contained on the site. | These cookies are prefixed as: ki_r; ki_t; and ki_u. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Marketo | This cookie allows a website to link visitor behavior to a recipient of an email marketing campaign, to measure campaign effectiveness. | This cookie is identified as “_mkto_trk.” |  First Party; 

Persistent   
  
New Relic | This cookie is used to analyse the use of the site to enable troubleshooting and performance monitoring. No personal information is stored by this cookie. | These cookies are identified as: utag_main, _gat, login_service_login_newrelic_com_tokens, _ga, _gali. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Pingdom | This cookie is used to speed up page load times. The main purpose of this cookie is related to site performance. | This cookie is identified as: “__cfduid.” |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Quantcast (also known as Quantserve) | These cookies are used to measure insights from audience segments including site traffic and demographic information about the visitor. | These cookies are identified as: MC; serving.sys.com; and __qca. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Simpli.fi | These cookies are used to limit the number of times a visitor sees an advertisement as well as to help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. | These cookies are identified as: Uid and uid_syncd. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
Sizmek (also known as Media Mind) | These cookies are used to assess the effectiveness of banner ads and to ensure that a visitor is not exposed to the same advertisement multiple times. This does not contain personal or sensitive information. | These cookies are identified as: U2; A5; and ActivityInfo2. |  Third Party; 

Persistent   
  
1 A “First Party Cookie” means a cookie that is hosted with the same domain name (e.g. www.solarwinds.com).

2 A “Persistent Cookie” means that the cookie is not deleted from your device after you leave the website. They remain on your device for a longer period of time

3 A “Session Cookie” means that the cookie is deleted from your device after you leave the website.

If SolarWinds implements other cookies in future, we will update the text and table above with details of these cookies.

_Tracking Options and California Do No Track Disclosures._ You may adjust your browser settings to limit this tracking or to decline cookies, but by doing so, you may not be able to use certain features on the Website or take full advantage of our offerings. Our system may not respond to Do Not Track requests or headers from some or all browsers. To learn more about the use of cookies or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising and your choices about not having this information used by certain service providers, please click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) (for users in the United States) or click [here](http://youronlinechoices.eu/) (for users in the European Union).

_Information Collected from Other Sources._ SolarWinds may obtain information about you from other sources, including updated addresses or contact information, demographic information, and other publicly available data.

_Combination of Information_. SolarWinds may combine the information it receives from and about you including personal information, non-personal information, and information collected offline, as well as information collected from third party sources.

* Data Use 

SolarWinds, and its family of SolarWinds companies, may use the information we collect from and about you to:

  * Analyze the data for internal purposes, such as providing user support, responding to your requests for information, fulfilling orders, processing payments and preventing transactional fraud, providing SolarWinds products and services, and contacting you;
  * Develop new products and services;
  * Provide you with customized content, targeted offers, and advertising on the Website, other websites, or via telephone or email (if you have agreed to such communications);
  * Contact you with information, newsletters, and promotional material from SolarWinds or on behalf of our partners, (if you have agreed to such communications);
  * Research, address problems, and improve the usage and operations of the Website;
  * Protect the security or integrity of the Website and our business; and
  * As described to you at the point of data collection.

* Data Sharing 

SolarWinds may disclose the information we collect from and about you (a) to our third party service providers, if the disclosure will enable the service provider to perform a business, professional, or technical support function for SolarWinds; (b) in association with law enforcement, fraud prevention, a subpoena, or other legal or government investigatory action; (c) as required by law, rule, or regulation; (d) if SolarWinds reasonably believes it is required to protect SolarWinds, its customers, or the public; or (e) as described to you and the point of collection.

SolarWinds may provide aggregated statistics about users to third parties, but such information will be aggregated so that it does not identify a particular individual or company.

SolarWinds may sell or purchase assets during the normal course of our business. If another entity acquires SolarWinds or any of our assets, information we have collected about you may be transferred to such entity. In addition, if any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding is brought by or against us, such information may be considered an asset of ours and may be sold or transferred to third parties. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use personal information provided through the Website in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

* Data Storage 

As SolarWinds operates globally, we may transfer your personal information among our global locations, including countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Your personal information may be stored on servers in these various global locations. For EEA residents, we will utilize commercially reasonable measures to ensure that your personal information receives the same level of protection as it would had it stayed within the EEA, including seeking to ensure that it is kept secure and used only in accordance with our instructions and for the agreed purpose(s). Additionally, your personal information may be subject to the laws of other countries, where the data protection and other laws may differ from those of your country of residence. Your personal information may be disclosed in response to inquiries or requests from government authorities in the countries in which we operate.

* Marketing Choice/Opt-Out 

SolarWinds may periodically send you information regarding SolarWinds, its products or its partners. If you no longer wish to continue receiving such information, please click the “unsubscribe” link available at the bottom of the relevant email. You can also contact SolarWinds at [marketing@solarwinds.com](mailto:marketing@solarwinds.com) or at [unsubscribe@solarwinds.com](mailto:unsubscribe@solarwinds.com), and let SolarWinds know that you no longer wish to receive such information. Alternatively, you can reply to an email from SolarWinds and type "REMOVE" in the subject line.

* Public Forums 

Any information you may disclose on community forums or other public areas of the Website becomes public information. Please exercise caution when disclosing personal information in these public areas, as SolarWinds has no control over who has access or will utilize said information.

* Third Party Sites 

The Website may include links to third party websites. SolarWinds does not own or control these third party websites and these links are for convenience only. SolarWinds is not responsible for the availability, content, data collection, utilization of data, use of cookies, or otherwise on the third party websites. If you have any questions about how such third parties’ privacy and data use practices, you should contact such third parties directly.

* Update and Access to Information 

Certain areas of this Website will require you to provide certain personal information. It is your responsibility to provide the most recent available and accurate information. Additionally, please inform SolarWinds of any change of name, address, or other information. You have the right, subject to certain exemptions, to obtain a copy of any personal data we hold about you and to correct any inaccuracies in such data. If you wish to avail of any of these rights, please contact us at: [marketing@solarwinds.com](mailto:marketing@solarwinds.com). Your request will be dealt with as soon as possible and in any event, within 40 days. If you have created an account on the Website, you may update certain information in your account profile. In addition, you may request that SolarWinds update, modify, or delete your registered information by sending an email to [marketing@solarwinds.com](mailto:marketing@solarwinds.com) with the words "UPDATE USER INFORMATION" in the subject line.

* Security 

SolarWinds uses commercially reasonable security measures, and strives to safeguard information concerning, and submitted by, users. Despite the security measures employed by SolarWinds, users should be aware that it is impossible to guarantee absolute security with respect to electronic information, and User agrees and accepts the risks associated with the same.

* Questions 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement or our data handling practices, you may contact us at [marketing@solarwinds.com](mailto:marketing@solarwinds.com).

* Modifications to this Privacy Statement 

This Privacy Statement and the Terms of Use of the SolarWinds Website constitute the complete agreement between the parties with respect to their subject matter and supersede any prior agreement or communication. SolarWinds reserves the right to modify this Privacy Statement. In the event SolarWinds updates or modifies this Privacy Statement, SolarWinds shall endeavor to post such updates or modifications on this Website following any such modifications. It we update or modify the Privacy Statement in a material way, we will utilize commercially reasonable efforts to provide appropriate notice to you.

© 2014 SolarWinds Worldwide, LLC. All Rights Reserved.  
Last Updated 12/08/14
